Selected Compositions of Elliot Griffis
Yale University Music Library
Selected Compositions of Elliot Griffis
1919-1964
Misc. Ms. 53
Yale University Music Library
0.5
(1 box)
Published and unpublished music and other materials by and about the American composer Elliot Griffis (1893-1967)
Griffis, Elliot, 1893-1967
Conditions Governing Access
Griffis's compositions are open to researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The collection was established in the Music Library of Yale University by Ellsworth Grumman, Roland Tiemann, and Luther Noss.
Arrangement
In 2 series as follows: I. Music. II. Miscellaneous.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists primarily of published piano music, songs, and the violin sonata by Elliot Griffis. The collection also holds a holograph score of the composer's Intrata for piano, as well as photocopies of holograph scores for 7 other compositions. The last folder of the collection contains a small amount of biographical material, including portraits, programs, and reviews.
Biographical / Historical
Elliot Griffis was born on January 28, 1893 in Boston. He was educated at Ithaca College, the Yale School of Music (where he studied with Horatio Parker), and the New England Conservatory. He taught at numerous schools and performed widely as a pianist, before moving to Los Angeles to compose film music. He died there on June 8, 1967.
Piano music; Sonatas (Violin and piano) -- Scores and parts; Songs
- Music, Series I
  - Piano Music, I.A
    - À La Chaconne Op. 12, No. 2: Study for the Left Hand Alone (Box 1, Folder 1)
      General
      Schroeder & Gunther (1923) New York
    - Arabesque, For Piano (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Carlvi Music Company, Ltd. (1956) Hollywood, Calif.
      (signed by composer)
    - Arabesque, For Piano (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Composers Press, Inc. (1956) Brooklyn, N.Y.
    - Bluebell Op. 15, No. 3 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Composer's Music Corporation (1922) New York
    - Bluebell Op. 15, No. 3 (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Carlvi Music Company, Ltd. (1957) Hollywood, Calif.
      (2 copies, both signed by composer)
    - Corporal Lollipop, G.C.M. (Box 1, Folder 1)
      Theodore Presser Co. (1951) Bryn Mawr, Pa.
      (2 copies)
    - Dixie Parade: March for Piano (Box 1, Folder 2)
      D.L. Schroeder (1930) Flushing, N.Y.
    - For A Broken Doll (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Composers Press, Inc. (1960) Brooklyn, N.Y.
    - A Fun Package: Ragtime with a Modern Touch (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Robert B. Brown Music Co. (1964) Hollywood, Calif,
    - Ghosts: A Keyboard Palpitation (Box 1, Folder 2)
    - Happy Song (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Also included: Workout for the Left Hand (Hornpipe)
      Carlvi Music Company, Ltd. (1958) Hollywood, Calif.
    - Invention: Piano Solo in Two-part Counterpoint (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Clayton F. Summy Co. (1951)
    - Jig (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Oliver Ditson Company (1942) Philadelphia, Pa.
    - Julianne: Waltz Memories of Vienna (Box 1, Folder 2)
      Composers Press, Inc. (1937) Brooklyn, N.Y.
      (2 copies, 1 signed by composer)
    - Letters From A Maine Farm: Seven Pieces for the Piano (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Scope and Contents
      Homage to MacDowell
      The Spider at My Window
      Woodchucks
      The Music Box
      The Girl on the Farm Below
      The Sunlit Woods
      A Forgotten Poem
      Composers' Music Corporation (no date), New York
      (signed by composer, 1924)
    - Letters From A Maine Farm (Box 1, Folder 3)
      Individual copies
      - The Girl On The Farm Below Op. 9, No. 5
        Carl Fischer, Inc, (1924) New York
        (3 copies, 2 signed by composer)
      - The Music Box Op. 9, No. 4
        Carl Fischer, Inc. (1957) New York
      - The Spider At My Window Op. 9, No. 2
        Carl Fischer, Inc. (1960) New York
    - Nina (Box 1, Folder 4)
    - Nocturne: Poem for Piano (Box 1, Folder 4)
      D.L. Schroeder (1951) Flushing, N.Y.
      (3 copies, 1 signed by composer)
    - Piece For The Left Hand: À la chaconne (Box 1, Folder 4)
      D.L. Schroeder (1948) Flushing, N.Y.
      (4 copies)
    - Rousseau Variations: Melody by Jean Jacques Rousseau (Box 1, Folder 5)
    - "A Set Of Eight": Poems and Studies for Piano (Box 1, Folder 6)
      1. Intrata
      2. Improvisation
      3. Summer
      4. Brief Stanza
      5. Fantasie
      6. A Child Asleep
      7. The North Wind
      8. The Willow Tree
      Composers Press, Inc. (1936) Brooklyn, N.Y.
      (3 copies, all signed by composer)
    - Brief Stanza (Box 1, Folder 6)
      Composers Press, Inc, (1936) Brooklyn, N.Y.
      (copy)
    - Sonata In A-Flat Major For Piano (Box 1, Folder 7)
      I. The Palace
      II. The Lake
      III. The Goblins
      IV. The Fête
      Composers' Music Corporation (1919) New York
    - Tango Español: Spanish Tango (Box 1, Folder 8)
      (3 copies)
    - Teddie And The Terrible Dodum: From "Ten Little Stories" (Box 1, Folder 8)
    - A Thought: Pensée (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Art Publication Society (1936) St. Louis, Mo.
    - To A Daffodil: Mélodie (Box 1, Folder 8)
      Schroeder & Gunther, Inc. (1922) New York
    - Transmutations: 44 Developments of a Five-measure Original Theme for Piano (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Three Dances (Box 1, Folder 9)
      30. Upswing
      31. Polka
      33. Tango
    - Dances (Box 1, Folder 9)
      39. Second Waltz
      40. At Your Pleasure
    - Trillium Op. 15, No. 9 (Box 1, Folder 10)
      Composers' Music Corporation (1922) New York
    - Tunes For 2, 3, And 4 Hands: A Book of Duets for a Beginner and an Experienced Player (Box 1, Folder 10)
      D.L. Schroeder (1943) Flushing, N.Y.
    - Workout For The Left Hand: Hornpipe (Box 1, Folder 10)
      See: Happy Song
    - Yellow Rose: Mazurka for Piano (Box 1, Folder 10)
      D.L. Schroeder (1947) Flushing, N.Y.
  - Violin Music, I.B
    - Sonata For Violin And Piano In G Major (Box 1, Folder 11)
      Composers Press, Inc. (1941) New York
  - Vocal Music, I.C
    - A Caravan From China Comes: After Hafiz (Box 1, Folder 12)
      Composers' Music Corporation (1920) New York
    - Dawn Song (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Dorado (Box 1, Folder 12)
      See: Songs From Poe
    - The Enchanted Hour: High voice (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Goldenhair: High voice (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Men Are The Devil: Medium voice (Box 1, Folder 12)
      (2 copies, signed by composer)
    - The Mountains: Medium voice (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - The Mountains: Medium voice (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Romance: Song (Box 1, Folder 13)
      D.L. Schroeder (1928) Flushing, N.Y.
    - Songs From Poe: medium voice (Box 1, Folder 14)
      To The River
      Eldorado
      (4 copies, 2 signed by composer)
    - Sunlight And Shadow Op. 16, Nos. 1-7 (Box 1, Folder 15)
      Prelude
      Sun Prayer
      Shadows
      Wind Prayer
      The Grapes
      Rain
      Dusk
      Schroeder & Gunther, Inc. (1924) New York
    - To An Iris: medium voice (Box 1, Folder 16)
      G. Schirmer (1927) New York
    - To An Iris: medium voice (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - To The River (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Holographs And Facsimiles, I.D
    - Intrata: From "A Set of Eight Poems and Studies for Piano" (Box 1, Folder 17)
      (signed holograph)
    - Mazurkas In A Minor And B Minor For Piano, 1947 (Box 1, Folder 17)
      (facsimile)
    - Ostinato, For Organ (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Playa Laguna, For Piano (1953): Greetings from the Workshop of Elliot Griffis (Box 1, Folder 17)
      (3 facsimiles)
    - Tango Marcella, For Piano (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Transmutations 1945: 43 Developments of a Five-measure Theme for Piano (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Transmutations (Box 1, Folder 17)
      Early sketches, see: Composer's letter to Roland Tiemann
    - Yellow Rose: Mazurka for Piano (Box 1, Folder 17)
- Miscellaneous, Series II
  - Correspondence, Photographs, Miscellaneous (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Autograph letter signed to Roland Tiemann, 3 November 1944
      (On back, early sketches of "Transmutations, for Piano")
    - Self Portrait - Elliot Griffis, no date
      (drawing)
    - Photographed drawing of Elliot Griffis, 1924
    - Catalogue of published music: Carlvi Music Company, Ltd. (1956) Hollywood, Calif.
    - Discography - Music of Elliot Griffis: Bureau of Auditory Education (no date) Hollywood, Calif.
    - Program of Elliot Griffis' music: Composers' Music Corporation (no date)
    - Reviews of Elliot Griffis' music: D.L. Schroeder (no date) Flushing, N.Y.
    - Review of Elliot Griffis' music: St. Louis Globe-Democrat (no date)